sortlist.com 2019-04-30

# Privacy - Sortlist

The Sortlist Privacy Policy is an agreement between Sortlist SA (hereinafter referred to as "Sortlist", "We", "Us" or "Our"), and the User.

Sortlist is an online platform that connects Agencies with Project Owners through a selection process. Sortlist's services are to set up advanced marketing and commercial prospecting techniques to explore the market and identify Project Owners that are actively looking for Marketing Agencies. Sortlist then verifies the Projects, creates Anonymous Briefs, selects a limited number of Agencies and allows these Agencies to accept the opportunities that are relevant for them and collaborate with the Project Owners on Projects.

Sortlist is committed to respecting and protecting the privacy of personal data collected on our Site.

This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you about how Sortlist treats Personal Information that Sortlist process about you. If you do not agree to any part of this Privacy Policy, then we cannot provide the Site or Services to you, and you should stop accessing the Site and deactivate your Sortlist Account.

## I. Key Terms

Where the definition of a term does not appear in this Privacy Policy, it shall be given its definition as outlined in our Terms of Use.

"Affiliates" means companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and non-financial companies.

"Aggregated Information" means information about all of our users or specific groups or categories of users that we combine together so that it no longer identifies or references an individual user.

"Data Controller" means Sortlist, the company responsible for the use and processing of Personal Information.

"Third Parties" means companies or persons not related by common ownership or control (i.e. non-affiliates) or other unrelated individuals. Third Parties can be financial and non-financial companies, or persons other than you and Sortlist.

"Personal Information" means information (which may include sensitive information) relating to a individual who is or can be identified either from that information or from that information in conjunction with other information that is in, or is likely to come into, the possession of the Data Controller.

## II. Information collected by Sortlist

### A. Information given by the Users

We receive, store and process information, including Personal Information that you make available to us when accessing or using our Site and Services. Examples include when you:

  * fill in any form on the Site with searching criteria of the service that you wish obtain (definition of the desired service, location of your company, your estimated budget, your company name, contact details, brief details, etc.);
  * you register or update the details of your user account, or when you supply verification information;
  * communicate with Sortlist; and
  * share information with another User.

### B. Information collected from the use of the Site by Users

We also receive, store and process information, possibly including Personal Information, when you access or use our Site and Services, including but not limited to:

  *  **Contact Information**

You may use your contact information, such as your email address, phone number. If you provide us with your email address, phone number, you agree to receive emails to that email address, text messages to that phone number, as the case may be. We may use your contact information to send you information about our Site and Services, to market to you, and to help prevent spam, fraud, or abuse.

  *  **Data related to your project**

We ay receive, store and process data related to your project which is information we need to draft an anonymous brief which is addressed to our Agencies members.

  *  **Log Data**

We ay also receive, store and process Log Data, which is information that is automatically recorded by our servers whenever you access or use the Site, regardless of whether you are registered with Sortlist or logged in to your Sortlist Account, such as your IP Address, the date and time you access or use the Site, the hardware and software you are using, referring and exit pages and URLs, the number of clicks, device event information, pages viewed and the order of those pages, and the amount of time spent on particular pages.

  *  **Cookies and similar technologies**

Sor list uses cookies and other similar technologies on the Site. We may also allow our business partners to use their cookies and other tracking technologies on the Site. As a result, when you access or use the Site, you will provide or make available certain information to us and to our business partners.

While you may disable the usage of cookies through your browser settings, we do not change our practices in response to a "Do Not Track" signal in the HTTP header from your browser. We track your activities if you click on advertisements for Sortlist services on Third-Party platforms such as search engines and social networks, and may use analytics to track what you do in response to those advertisements.

We may, either directly or through Third Parties we engage to provide services to us, also continue to track your behavior on our own Site for purposes of our own customer support, analytics, research, product development, fraud prevention, risk assessment, regulatory compliance, investigation, as well as to enable you to use and access the Site and pay for your activities on the Site. We may also, either directly or through Third-Parties we engage to provide services to us, track your behavior on our own Site to market and advertise our services to you on the Site and Third-Party websites. Third Parties that use cookies and other tracking technologies to deliver targeted advertisements on our Site and/or Third-Party websites may offer you a way to prevent such targeted advertisements by opting-out at the websites of industry groups such as the Network Advertising Initiative and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance. You may also be able to control advertising cookies provided by publishers, for example Google's Ad Preference Manager. Please note that even if you choose to opt-out of receiving targeted advertising, you may still receive advertising on or about the Site - it just will not be tailored to your interests. In addition, if you disable cookies, you may lose some of the features and functionality of using our Site and Services, as cookies are necessary to track and enhance your use and access.

Third Parties may not collect information about users' online activities on the Site except as described in this policy.

## III. How Sortlist uses information collected

### A. We use, store and process information about you for the following general purposes:

  * to enable you to access and use the Site and Services;
  * to enable you to communicate with other Users, including but not limited to by sending them messages or other information during the Selection process and drafting the Anonymous Briefs;
  * to operate, protect, improve and optimize the Site, Sortlist's business, and our users' experience, such as to perform analytics, conduct research, personalize or otherwise customize your experience, and to provide customer service;
  * to help create and maintain a trusted and safer environment on the Site and Services, such as detection and prevention of actual and potential fraud and other harmful activity, conducting investigations and risk assessments, enforcing our Terms and conditions, verifying the address of your listings, verifying any identifications provided by you (including by comparing the photo on that identification to another photo you provide to us), and conducting checks against databases and information sources (such as but not limited to public government databases) for fraud detection and prevention, risk assessment and harm prevention purposes. In this regard, we may do any or all of the foregoing with or without further notifying you;
  * to send you service, support and administrative messages, reminders, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and information requested by you;
  * to send you marketing, advertising, and promotional messages and other information that may be of interest to you, including information about Sortlist, our services, or general promotions for partner campaigns and services;
  * to administer referral programs, rewards, surveys, sweepstakes, contests, or other promotional activities or events sponsored or managed by Sortlist or our Third Party business partners; and
  * to comply with our legal obligations, resolve any disputes that we may have with any of our users, and enforce our agreements with Third Parties.

### B. How Sortlist uses and processes user communications:

We may, either directly or through Third-Parties we engage to provide services to us, review, scan, or analyze your communications with other users exchanged via the Site for fraud prevention, risk assessment, regulatory compliance, investigation, product development, research and customer support purposes. For example, as part of our fraud prevention efforts, the Site may scan and analyze messages and attachments to mask contact information and references to other websites. We may also scan, review or analyze messages for research and product development purposes to help make search and user communications more efficient and effective, as well as to debug, improve and expand product offerings. We will also not sell these reviews or analyses of communications to Third Parties. We will also use automated methods to carry out these reviews or analyses where reasonably possible. However, from time to time we may have to manually review some communications. By using the Site and Services, you consent that Sortlist, in its sole discretion, may, either directly or through Third-Parties we engage to provide services to us, review, scan, analyze, and store your communications, whether done manually or through automated means.

## IV. State privacy laws

Our policy for the protection of your personal data is strictly compliant with the laws applicable in Belgium and the European Union:

  * the Belgian law of 8 December 1992 (the "privacy law") amended by the law of 11 December 1998 and in force since 1 September 2001;
  * European directive No 95/46/CE of 24 October 1995 on privacy protection

To verify whether our privacy policy is compliant with the above legal instruments, we called upon the services of an external company that specializes in the legal audit of sites.

Please note that we assume no responsibility regarding the privacy policy of the sites that are hyperlinked with our site.

## V. Business transfers by Sortlist

If Sortlist undertakes or is involved in any merger, acquisition, reorganization, sale of assets or bankruptcy or insolvency event, then we may sell, transfer or share some or all of our assets, including your Personal Information. In this event, we will notify you before your Personal Information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

## VI. How to access, change or delete your information, or cancel your Sortlist account

You may review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information in your Sortlist Account. If you would like to correct your information or cancel your Sortlist Account entirely, you can do so by logging in to your Sortlist Account. Please also note that any reviews, forum postings and similar materials posted by you may continue to be publicly available on the Site in association with your first name, even after your Sortlist Account is cancelled.

## VII. Securing your personal information

We are continuously implementing and updating administrative, technical, and physical security measures to help protect your Personal Information against unauthorized access, destruction or alteration. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, and no method of storing electronic information, can be 100% secure. So, we cannot guarantee the security of your transmissions to us and of your Personal Information that we store.

## VIII. Changes to this privacy policy

We may change how we collect and then use Personal Information at any time and without prior notice, at our sole discretion. We may change this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make material changes to the Privacy Policy, we will notify you either by posting the changed Privacy Policy on the Site or by sending an email to you. We will also update the "Last Updated" date at the top of this Privacy Policy. If we let you know of changes through an email communication, then the date on which we send the email will be deemed to be the date of your receipt of that email.

It's important that you review the changed Privacy Policy. If you do not wish to agree to the changed Privacy Policy, then we will not be able to continue providing the Site and Services to you, and your only option will be to stop accessing the Site and Services and deactivate your Sortlist Account. You can find out more about how to deactivate your Sortlist Account on our [FAQ](https://intercom.help/sortlist).

## IX. For users residing in the eu and japan only: your rights to review and update information

If you reside in the EU or Japan, you may request in writing copies of your Personal Information held by us. We will provide you with a copy of the Personal Information held by us as soon as practicable and in any event not more than 40 days after receiving a valid request in writing. We may also request proof of identification to verify your access request.

We endeavor to keep your information accurate, complete and up to date. If your Personal Information that we hold is inaccurate, please let us know and we will make the necessary amendments, erase or block the relevant information and notify you within 40 days of your valid request that the relevant action has been taken.

You may also request the erasure of your Personal Information if you believe we are otherwise in breach of relevant data protection legislation. All requests should be addressed to Sorlist. There is no charge for making such a request.

## X. Cookie policy

Sortlist uses "cookies" in conjunction with the Site to obtain information. A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to your device (e.g. your phone or your computer) for record-keeping purposes. For example, a cookie could allow the Site to recognize your browser, while another could store your preferences and other information.

Your browser may allow you to set how it handles cookies, such as declining all cookies or prompting you to decide whether to accept each cookie. But please note that some parts of the Site may not work as intended or may not work at all without cookies.

### A. Sortlist cookies and Third Party cookies

Sortlist may place our cookies on your device via the Site. Accordingly, our Privacy Policy will apply to our treatment of the information we obtain via our cookies.

We may also allow our business partners to place cookies on your device. For example, we use Google Analytics for web analytics, and so Google may also set cookies on your device. As further explained below, Third Parties may also place cookies on your device for advertising purposes.

There are two types of cookies used on the Site, namely "persistent cookies" and "session cookies".

Session cookies will normally expire when you close your browser, while persistent cookies will remain on your device after you close your browser, and can be used again the next time you access the Site.

### B. Other technologies

The Site may also use other technologies with similar functionality to cookies, such as web beacons and tracking URLs to obtain Log Data about users. We may also use web beacons and tracking URLs in our messages to you to determine whether you have opened a certain message or accessed a certain link.

### C. Uses for Sortlist cookies

Sortlist uses cookies and similar tracking technologies for a number of purposes, such as the following:

  * to enable, facilitate and streamline the functioning of the Site across different webpages, devices and browser sessions.
  * to simplify your access to and use of the Site and make it more seamless.
  * to monitor and analyze the performance, operation and effectiveness of the Site, so that we can improve and optimize it.
  * to show you content (which may include advertisements) that is more relevant to you.
  * for fraud detection and prevention.

### D. Uses for Third-Party cookies

Our partners' cookies are intended to obtain information to help them provide services to Sortlist. For example, Third Parties we engage to provide services to us may track your behavior on our Site to market and advertise Sortlist listings or services to you on the Site and Third-party websites, or to help us detect or prevent fraud or conduct risk assessments. Third Parties websites that use cookies and other tracking technologies to deliver targeted advertisements on our Site and/or Third-Party websites may offer you a way to prevent such targeted advertisements by opting-out at the websites of industry groups. You may also be able to control advertising cookies provided by publishers, for example Google's Ad Preference Manager. Please note that even if you choose to opt-out of receiving targeted advertising, you may still receive advertising on or about the Site - it just will not be tailored to your interests.

### E. Disabling Cookies

Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can modify your browser setting to decline cookies by visiting the Help portion of your browser's toolbar. If you choose to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in, customize, or use some of the interactive features of the Site. Flash cookies operate differently than browser cookies, and cookie management tools available in a web browser will not remove flash cookies. To learn more about how to manage flash cookies, you can visit the Adobe website and make changes at the Global Privacy Settings Panel.

### F. Changes to this Cookie Policy

We can change this Cookie Policy at any time. If we make material changes to the Cookie Policy, we will let you know either by posting the changed Cookie Policy on the Site or by sending you an email.

It's important that you review the changed Cookie Policy. If you do not wish to agree to the changed Cookie Policy, then we cannot continue to provide the Site

to you, and your only option is to stop accessing the Site and Services and deactivate your Sortlist Account. You can find out more about how to deactivate your Sortlist Account on our [FAQ](https://intercom.help/sortlist).
